<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mullings</title>
    <description>Sharing thoughts and reflections with whoever is interested.</description>
    <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://mullings.robopoto.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 03:09:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 03:09:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Mass Effect a Cure for Paralysis of Analysis?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have struggled with indecision born of perfectionism. It seems to be related to loss aversion, .ie., the fear of missing out (FOMO). I knew this was something I needed to work through, and I found some help in a videogame series known as Mass Effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mass Effect, you are forced to make decisions that have lasting consequences for the rest of the game and even future games. Characters and people groups will potentially live or die by the choices you make. Additionally, the game permits your choices to be misunderstood, leading to unexpected outcomes. All-in-all this game caused me some anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to make the perfect decision, but there’s not always enough information to make the best decision. Additionally, even seemingly well-thought-out choices don’t always lead to the best outcomes. I decided to use this game for my growth by never changing a previous choice. Doing this enabled me to make decisions associated with leadership without the same level of consequence.  I also had to work through various negative emotions that would plague me as played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It definitely helped me accommodate to the pain of making the “wrong” choices. It helped me remember that even if you make all the supposedly right choices, you still get less than desirable outcomes. It ended up being more difficult than I thought, but it was rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you are struggling with perfectionism or related weaknesses. In that case, I’d recommend you try Mass Effect, but if you’re not into video games, the principle still holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find an activity that will activate your indecision, preferably an activity with a quick feedback loop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give yourself a short time limit to make a decision.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work through any adverse feelings you get from the process, preferably with a friend/counselor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t approach this as a blank slate. I already had some decision-making shortcuts that helped with the mildly consequently choices. For example, if I wasn’t sure about a decision, I would go with my initial gut instinct. Other times, if the decision is far beyond my ability to grapple, I might introduce randomness, a coin flip. Having some good strategies will definitely help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/mass-effect-the-cure-for-paralysis-of-analysis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/mass-effect-the-cure-for-paralysis-of-analysis/</guid>
        
        
        <category>mass effect</category>
        
        <category>paralysis of analysis</category>
        
        <category>decision making</category>
        
        <category>overcoming</category>
        
        <category>journal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not feeling productive?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many, I struggle with never feeling productive enough. I work all day, but unless I reach some undefined, illusive marker, my day is a wash. This often leads to long days and long nights. I find it frustrating and it leads to a lack of motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address this I’ve heard a few suggestions, some of which I’ve implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define success&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate success&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t compare.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand human limitation, i.e. your limitations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on one thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First it’s important to define success. If we don’t have a reasonable goal, we can find ourselves missing all the work we are accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another rule is we need to celebrate our successes. After we’ve accomplished a goal sometimes it’s tempting to minimise it, but if we take a moment to pat ourselves on the back we can begin to defeat the negative self-speak. Additionally, consider journalling, it’s a great way to capture your day and help you see where you were productive and where some bad habits are preventing productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid unhealthy comparison, sometimes the problem lies here. We see someone else who is much more productive and we feel that then devalues our productivity. That simply isn’t true. Whether we like it or not, we need to remember we are not the pennacle of humanity. We are not them, and they are not us. We all have different strengths and weaknesses. Some people have more strengths than others and that’s okay. You need to do well according to your ability and that’s has to be enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand your limitation. Our brains only have so much capacity for focused thought before it becomes difficult. I believe the average person has about 4-5 hours of focused usage of the prefrontal cortex before you fizzle out. Understand that will power isn’t going to help you overcome this limitation, at least not that I know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are going to be times when your lack of productivity comes from bad habits as well. In my case, I try to do too many things at once. Write a blog, do some contract work, study a new technology and build a website all in one day. Being so divided makes it difficult to make any progress in any one of those areas. Often we need to pick on thing and devote a block of time to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/not-feeling-productive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/not-feeling-productive/</guid>
        
        
        <category>sleep</category>
        
        <category>rest</category>
        
        <category>relaxation</category>
        
        <category>mind</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Castlevania... teaches empathy?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched the first episode of Castlevania, season 4, and they opened with some lines from the end of the previous season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sypha: This could not have gone more wrong, what happened?
Belmont: We’ve spent a couple of months living your life, adventures and victories. Now, we’re living my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For context, Belmont’s life consisted of fighting monsters and seeing the darker side of humanity, while Sypha has been traveling with a scholarly, idealistic, altruistic group. Belmont is often given a hard time throughout the series for his gloomy attitude, but in season 4, the other characters relate to his experience. They even find themselves thinking and behaving more like him. I appreciated that the show highlighted this transformation in Sypha and Alucard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this interesting because it highlights how circumstances form the way we perceive the world. Sypha lived in the Ivory Tower, so to speak, and she was very hopeful and optimistic. Then she started trying to help people against overwhelming odds, i.e., live Belmont’s life, and quickly discovered life wasn’t all rainbows and gummies. She is now able to understand why Belmont is the way he is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s imperative that we also understand that people see the world very differently from us. Whether it’s right or wrong isn’t the first question we need to ask. Instead, it’s more helpful to ask how they got to that worldview. It’s often hubris to assume we can convince someone that they need to think how we think. Instead, we should try to feel their feelings in the circumstances that led them to view the world the way they do. After that, we can address others with empathetic understanding and hopefully offend less often.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/castlevania-teaches-empathy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/castlevania-teaches-empathy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Castlevania</category>
        
        <category>Netflix</category>
        
        <category>empathy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When life gives you lemons, read manga</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;*Spoiler alert for Demon Slayer after the Mugen Train arc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent part of the weekend complaining with a friend about how bad church doctrine ruined important parts of our lives. Even though we’ve grown and overcome many of those ideas, we still feel the consequences of those teachings. Unfortunately, those are still years of our lives we can never get back, and we’re still suffering from the decisions we made based on those ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my flight back home, I was reading Demon Slayer, chapter 69. At this point in the story, the main character, Tanjiro, has watched more people die without having the power to do anything to stop it. He’s in mourning and struggling with his weakness. He says he wishes there was a way to instantly become strong enough to have protected his comrade but accepts the fact that there is “no such method.” He then says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only option is to struggle on. All I can do is move forward no matter how difficult or frustrating it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my context, this statement really hit home. It was a reminder that even though life might give lemons, even though you might make mistakes, even though bad things happen to us all. Mourning, in my case complaining, isn’t a solution, at most it’s a part of the process. Therefore, a meaningful option is to move forward in a positive direction. That isn’t to say everything will work out and life will eventually be rainbows and gummy bears, but hopefully, as you move forward, future joys will overshadow past pains or give hope that tomorrow will be better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/when-life-gives-you-lemons-read-manga/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/when-life-gives-you-lemons-read-manga/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Demon Slayer</category>
        
        <category>manga</category>
        
        <category>complaining</category>
        
        <category>moving forward</category>
        
        <category>hope</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are the same experiences required for empathy?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had several discussion in the past few month about people with charmed lives. These are people for whom life was relatively easy, not necessarily perfect, but low resistance. For example, consider a person who’s slightly overweight who decides to start working out and with a little instruction develops a habit and physique. Another example, what is the person who find “the [actual] one” the first time they date. Now imagine this is how this person lives most of there lives, this is what we described as a &lt;em&gt;charmed life&lt;/em&gt;. It’s not to say that these people do not experience difficulties, it’s to suggest they don’t experience any major difficulties that they cannot overcome through will and wit. These people do not necessarily understand the struggle that many others have with building a habit or ending multiple relationships. They haven’t experienced what it means to struggle in these areas without a positive outcome. All this to say, they cannot empathize with a non-insignificant portion of the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lead me to wonder what is the connection is between empathy and experience. I believe the answer to this question is yes, though not necessarily the exact same scenario, but the same feelings and parallel. For example, someone who feels trapped in a marriage might be able to empathize with an addict, given they both have experienced some level of hopelessness. Likewise, someone who is struggling with opening up because they’ve been burned emotionally might be able to relate to a person who’s afraid to connect because they’ve been lost their closest relationships to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind these examples, I don’t know if I believe you can effectively empathize without some comparative experience. Even if you believe your story compares, the other person needs to believe you understand their experience also.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/are-same-experiences-required-for-empathy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/are-same-experiences-required-for-empathy/</guid>
        
        <category>empathy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How do you be vulnerable?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to research-based self-improvement books is a hobby of mine. One of my
favorite authors is Brene Brown who wrote on the power of vulnerability. As I
listened to the book, it quickly became apparent that I had built up walls and
needed to become more vulnerable. The question was, “how do you be vulnerable?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I came to understand the idea of vulnerability and how it looked in
other people’s lives, I realized those examples didn’t translate well to my
life. I’ve learned that when I’m not sure about something within myself, I need
to watch myself for a while. I do this in two ways, 1) I try to relive moments
in my mind and see what feelings it invokes, 2) I pay attention to how I feel
in real time. After doing these exercises I was able to figure out when I life
was giving me an opportunity to be vulnerable. It’s when I hesitate to say or
do something because something inside me is afraid of how I’ll be received. I
have come to believe that if there isn’t some level of discomfort that I’m not
actually being vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/how-do-you-be-vulnerable/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/how-do-you-be-vulnerable/</guid>
        
        <category>vulnerability</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Did God really speak to that person?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve often struggled with is when people talk about how God told them to do something. Most of the time my skepticism is determined to be reality. Though their are those rare instances, where everything seems to line up in a way that suggest maybe, just maybe, their was some divine direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, when God leads a person, it will play out like a man living their life and less like a person getting clear, direct instructions from above. I think the reason you hear people talk about hearing God’s voice the way they do is because of the popular Christian themes that exist today have a very pentecostal root. We’ve been taught to expect God to speak to us “clearly”, so much so we seek it often to our disappointment, or force it to our inevitable embarrassment. It reminds me of a verse, which I particularly like in the KJV style:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For now we see through a glass, darkly;
1 Corinthians 13:12a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of spending so much effort removing all the uncertainty from our lives, we should instead learn to trust the Son and to love as Christ loved us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 01:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/god-speaking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/god-speaking/</guid>
        
        <category>god speaking</category>
        
        <category>uncertainty</category>
        
        <category>direction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What do I really want?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During a book club on “How to Win Friends and Influence People”, one of the members mentioned something a co-worker said to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you want?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you act like you want?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so true, we often say we want success, but do are actions and step agree?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://mullings.robopoto.com/what-you-say-what-you-do/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mullings.robopoto.com/what-you-say-what-you-do/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Desire</category>
        
        <category>Action</category>
        
        <category>Book</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
